NEHA SHARMA

Curriculum Vitae

nsa84@sfu.ca °

CAREER FOCUS

I am pursuing my Ph.D. in Computing Science under Prof. Mohamed Hefeeda at the Network Systems Lab, Simon Fraser University, Burnaby. My current research interests lie in multimedia networking, machine learning, deep learning and computer vision.

EDUCATION

Simon Fraser University, Burnaby (NSL)

Ph.D. in Computing Science - CGPA 3.84

Motilal Nehru National Institute of Technology, Allahabad

B.Tech. in Computer Science

Sep 2018 – present

Jul 2011 – May 2015

RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

Simon Fraser University Burnaby (NSL)

Sep 2018 – present

Research Assistant in the Network Systems Lab

- Hyperspectral imaging using deep learning models for mobile applications

University at Albany, SUNY

Jun 2017 - Nov 2017

Research Intern(remote) w/ Prof. Pradeep Atrey

SecureCMerge: Secure PDF Merging Over Untrusted Servers

- It is a method for secure PDF merging over untrusted third-party servers using the mergehomomorphism property of Shamir's secret sharing. It is developed as a Windows based application.
- Application is implemented in C#, PDF content extraction is done using third party library PDF4NET and PDF merging is done using third-party servers like pdfmerge.com (HTTP POST request).
- Kindly find the demo link of the application [https://youtu.be/UMOMhQiT928]

Indian Institute of Technology, Roorkee

Dec 2013

Research Intern w/ Prof. R. Balasubramanian

Image Compression using Huffman coding and JPEG

- Images are compressed using two techniques Huffman coding and JPEG, detailed analysis is performed using compression ratios of many images.
- Both the techniques are implemented in MATLAB

Motilal Nehru National Institute of Technology, Allahabad

Jul 2014 - May 2015

Undergraduate Research Project w/ Prof. Krishna K. Mishra

Multi-Objective Optimization using Non Dominated Sorting PSO

- The project involves implementation of modified PSO: Non-dominated Sorting Particle Swarm Optimization (NSPSO) for optimization of multiobjective functions as in CEC2009 benchmark functions. NSPSO extends the basic form of PSO by using effective non-dominated comparisons of a particle's best with its offspring. This proves to be effective in providing an appropriate selection pressure to propel the swarm population towards the Pareto-optimal front and give the optimal solution.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Infoedge India Limited (99acres.com)

Jun 2016 - Aug 2018

Senior Software Engineer

- Designed and implemented consolidated user management system to perform authentication and authorization of all users, with privilege management based on RBAC and DAC model.
- Devised a generic event based auditing framework for screening workflows of property and profile, such that, integration of framework can be done using annotations only.
- Analyzing software requirements to provide optimized design, evaluation, conceptualization, technology mapping and final execution.
- Performing Code Reviews, Quality Check, Deployment, Live Monitoring, Performance Testing and Scrum Master role in agile workflow.
- Mentoring the new joinees on the domain and process knowledge.

Infoedge India Limited (99acres.com)

Jun 2015 – May 2016

Software Engineer

- Migrated Legacy core module to the Web Services architecture using JAVA/ SPRING framework.
- SEO(Search Engine Optimization) projects, including successful HTTPS migration of site, meta tags optimization, page linking which led to increase in organic site traffic to around 10%.
- Designed architecture and implemented end to end solutions to meet business requirements.
- Gained exposure to all phases of the Software Development Life Cycle including Projects Planning & Implementation, Requirement Gathering and Analysis, Design & Development, Deployment, Testing and Maintenance.
- Developed and maintained core modules required by the application

PUBLICATIONS

- [1] Mohajerani, S., Asad, R., Abhishek, K., **Sharma, N.**, Duynhoven, A., Saeedi, P (2019). CloudMaskGAN: A Content-Aware Unpaired Image-to-Image Translation Algorithm for Remote Sensing Imagery. In IEEE International Conference on Image Processing (ICIP), 2019.
- [2] **Sharma, N.**, Singh, P., & Atrey, P. (2018). SecureCMerge: Secure PDF Merging Over Untrusted Servers. In IEEE 1st International Conference on Multimedia Information Processing and Retrieval (MIPR), 2018. [Acceptance Rate: **19.5**%]

AWARDS AND SCHOLARSHIPS	
Simon Fraser Graduate Fellowship Computer Research Association (Women) Research Scholar	Aug 2019 Apr 2019
AI Student Showcase Best Poster Award	Dec 2018
Simon Fraser Graduate Fellowship	Sep 2018
Simon Fraser Special Graduate Entrance Scholarship	Sep 2018

EXTRACURRICULAR ACTIVITIES

- Program Mentor at Invent the Future Event 2019 (AI4ALL) at SFU.
- Active participation in WiCS (Women in Computing Science) at SFU.
- Active participation in team building activities and hackathons in 99acres.
- Stage Play Winner in Culrav 2014, a national level cultural festival of MNNIT.
- Acted as Event coordinator of Cyberquest in Avishkar 2014, a national level technical festival of MNNIT.
- Was an active member of Drama Committee and Fashion Show Committee at MNNIT
- Won Fading Blue in Avishkar 2012, a national level technical festival of MNNIT.